const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"The hexose monophosphate (HMP) shunt occurs in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ribosome","bool":false},{"option":"Cytosol","bool":true},{"option":"Mitochondrion","bool":false},{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial matrix","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following represents Peyer's patches?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse lymph nodes in gastrointestinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoid aggregates in large intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes aggregates in duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoid aggregates in ileum","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following is the autonomous zone of the liver?","answers":[{"option":"Right lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Left lobe","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Quadrate lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate lobe","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which enzyme is deficient in von Gierke disease?","answers":[{"option":"6-phosphogluconolactonase (PGLS)","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphofructokinase (PFK)","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphatase (G6P)","bool":true},{"option":"6-Phosphogluconate dehydrogenase (6PGD)","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD)","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following is the normal serum bilirubin concentration?","answers":[{"option":"0.1-1.2 mg/dl","bool":true},{"option":"3.0-4.0 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"1.2-2.5 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"2.0-3.0 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"1.0-2.0 mg/dl","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following is a major cause of celiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"Tropheryma whippelii","bool":false},{"option":"Intussusception","bool":false},{"option":"Aldolase B deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Gliadin peptides","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"The body of the patient is found to produce endomysial antibodies with the intestinal biopsy showing the presence of flattened villi. Which of the following diseases is this hinting towards?","answers":[{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":true},{"option":"Lactose intolerance","bool":false},{"option":"Ménétrier disease","bool":false},{"option":"Whipple's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Grave's disease","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following is the rate-limiting enzyme in cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"HMG-CoA reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Prenyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Squalene synthase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Mevalonate carboxylase","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following is the active coenzyme form of vitamin B6?","answers":[{"option":"NAD","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxal 5-phosphate","bool":true},{"option":"FMN","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxamine","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Liver biopsy is performed at which of the following spaces?","answers":[{"option":"Subcostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Right 7th intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Right 10th intercostal space","bool":true},{"option":"5th intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"Right 8th intercostal space","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following is niacin derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Adenine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true},{"option":"Methionine","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"What is the regulatory step in endogenous cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Mevalonate","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG CoA reductase","bool":true},{"option":"HMG CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen synthase","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which enzyme deficiency occurs in Cori's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Debranching enzyme","bool":true},{"option":"Glycogen lyase","bool":false},{"option":"Pyruvate kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Branching enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen synthase","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Acetyl-CoA is used in the synthesis of cholesterol. Which of the following is the rate-limiting step for cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Synthesis of farnesyl","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesis of mevalonate","bool":true},{"option":"Synthesis of HMG-CoA","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesis of squalene","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesis of isopentenyl pyrophosphate (IPP)","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"In which part of the gastrointestinal tract is most of the vitamin b12 is absorbed?","answers":[{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Ileum","bool":true},{"option":"Jejunum","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Colon","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following is a glycogen disease that is related to lysosomes?","answers":[{"option":"Her's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Cori's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Von Gierke's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Pompe's disease","bool":true},{"option":"McArdle's disease","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following enzymes acts on alpha-ketoglutarate molecule involved in Kreb's cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Aconitase","bool":false},{"option":"Isocitrate dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Succinate dehyrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Citrate synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"What is the total ATP yield of Kreb's cycle?","answers":[{"option":"17","bool":false},{"option":"12","bool":true},{"option":"11","bool":false},{"option":"38","bool":false},{"option":"36","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following organs is not involved in the HMP shunt?","answers":[{"option":"Adipose tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Testes","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"What is the significance of 2,3 bisphosphate in RBCs?","answers":[{"option":"Used to increase hemoglobin binding to CO","bool":false},{"option":"Serves to increase O₂ delivery","bool":true},{"option":"Used to produce energy in RBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Serves to increase CO₂ delivery to tissues","bool":false},{"option":"Used to increase hemoglobin binding to O₂","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"What is the most common cause of pancreatitis?","answers":[{"option":"Autoimmune Disease","bool":false},{"option":"Scorpion sting","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol","bool":true},{"option":"Drugs","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"From which of the following arteries does the left colic artery arise?","answers":[{"option":"Abdominal aorta","bool":false},{"option":"ileocolic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior mesenteric artery","bool":true},{"option":"Superior mesenteric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Celiac artery","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following organs is in contact with the bare area of the liver?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":true},{"option":"Duodenum","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Damage to the posterior side of the canal would affect which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"External urethral sphincter","bool":false},{"option":"Anococcygeal ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Venous plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Ischioanal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Internal urethral sphincter","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"The anal canal above the pectinate line is supplied by which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Perineal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior hypogastric plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Superior hypogastric plexus","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"On ultrasonography and radiological examination, which of the following structures divides the liver into functional right and left lobes?","answers":[{"option":"Portal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Paraesophageal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Middle hepatic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"What structure lies medial to ischo-anal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial tuberosity","bool":false},{"option":"Pudendal canal","bool":false},{"option":"Levator ani","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following regarding celiac trunk is not true?","answers":[{"option":"Arises at the level of aortic hiatus","bool":false},{"option":"It has three main arterial branches","bool":false},{"option":"It is responsible for blood supply to pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"It is responsible for blood supply to jejunum","bool":true},{"option":"It arises at the level of T12-L1","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"Which of the following is a ventral mesogastrium derivative?","answers":[{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Ileorenal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Greater omentum","bool":false},{"option":"Falciform ligament","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2016","question":"There is a part of the gastrointestinal tract that is covered by the peritoneum for the first few centimeters and then gets retroperitoneal. This is correct about which part of the gastrointestinal tract?","answers":[{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenum","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Ileum","bool":false},{"option":"Jejunum","bool":false}]}]
export default arr